Today's date and time item 2 is public input and then schedule personal periods. So in the
audience it was used to address the council on an area agenda items. They're being
none item 3 is constant agenda. Staff is recommending items for 12 for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items, that anything in the motion to approve.
Most of the pretty much. Okay. And the second question.
Second roll call.
Johnson.
All right.
Most of the questions.
Closter.
All right.
Shelter.
All right. Thank you. I don't know 13 is capital features government relations.
LLC.
Plane of $3,000.
Do we have a motion to approve?
A motion to approve.
Okay.
And I'll second that roll call.
Place.
At first.
All right. Shelter.
All right.
Question.
Melissa.
Johnson.
No.
Okay.
Item 15.
Is this your contract for online bully training and author is on authorized.
City manager design.
Yeah.
Okay. Well, the reason this is an only consent agenda is because the city manager thought this was
good news that I needed to share with all of you.
So we're moving out of 1970 into 2017 and actually going to do some online training.
Working was strategic government resources SGR, which is a company.
Really, I think is the municipal government expert that we've used for many other things, training and recruitment.
What this does for us $29 an employee and a lot of training that we've done in the past.
We have mandatory training.
So we have to do workplace harassment training, safety trainings every year.
Every time we do one of those mandatory trainings, we spend about $2,500 in overtime for police
and fire workplace harassment training.
We spend about $1,500 to bring a vendor in.
So when we started looking at all the options through online training and eliminating that,
we are many thousands of dollars ahead by implementing this.
There are 94 different training modules.
Everything from it all help us with new employee orientation, seasonal employee orientation,
telephone skill training for local government employees, ethics, communication,
leadership, there's just all kinds of things.
So there will be mandatory trainings that HR will assign to every employee and then department heads
will be able to assign trainings that pertain to their area.
So we're asking you to optimize the signature on this contract for the city manager to sign it.
So is this a one-ton? So tell me about the cost structure again?
Sure, it's $29 per employee a year.
Yes. And they are actually, we've done some negotiation with them.
They're waving the $500 set up fee that they usually do and they're also waving the first month's fee,
which is $534. So we're spending $5,500.
If we do two mandatory trainings in-house, we spend $5,000 on over time and we have more
than that every year.
So, it is a contract that we can renew yearly, but we're not locked into it.
So, and they can train at their own convenience, right?
Exactly.
At their computer, you know, so police and fire department, instead of them having been here
to come in at 10 30, you know, they can do it at 830 in the evening when they're on shift.
It's just really a win-win, and I think it's a much better way to spend our dollars.
It's more convenient, and also we have tracking of what everybody trains.
So, we'll print out those certificates, put it in their personnel file.
It's just a much better way for us to track the training, and also for it to be more convenient for employees.
You may be brought up at points, so you can do that home.
Is that what we're going to recommend?
I'm sorry.
No.
You have to do it.
Okay, it's cool.
You can do it.
Why?
I just want to verify.
You have to be.
Because you have to watch them all night before you click the button.
Right.
But the reason we won't do it at home is a salary employee does that.
It's fine, but we don't want to get into wage in our issues.
So, it will be, you'll have to do it at work.
Sorry.
Well, we do it at time.
Absolutely.
But it won't be over time.
I'm just saying there are way first month's fee.
And there's just $29 per person.
But these are a monthly fee every month.
I guess.
We can choose to pay it.
It's a yearly fee.
So, we lock in with so many employees.
We may have employees that we add on.
We may have employees that go off.
But we're locked into that yearly fee.
We pay that.
We can pay it monthly.
We will probably do it so much easier, rather than putting it on the claims list.
It's almost as much as every six months.
But probably do two things.
And you're showing the math.
The math is going to be about $580.
The first month's fee.
Yes.
Awesome.
They make that worse.
It's come after you hire an employee, does this training have to be done?
Of course, there's something that they're after their own payroll.
A new employee orientation training.
We do within the first three days.
Okay.
It's for other training that comes throughout the year that you have to take.
Right.
So, harassment training you have to do yearly.
What we'll do is, when we send it to an employee, they'll have a link.
And they'll have a timeframe.
You have 30 days to complete it or whatever that is.
So, there will be different types of training going out throughout the year with different
time limits on it.
Okay.
I just, my head, I'm saying I'm no employee.
Do you get through the first 90 days?
Say they don't want to work here anymore.
Maybe even 30 days.
And you should have the time to do it.
Do you give a certain amount of time for a plan?
What we'll probably do is use that 90 day.
The probationary period to do some of the employee orientation stuff.
But we now do face-to-face.
But there is so much going on in the first 90 days.
We usually wait until after that.
And really for that very reason.
Okay.
I'd take it there, spare it in the budget.
Yes.
Okay.
We do this training at work.
It's convenient at a 10-year-old pace and on your own time.
There's so a lot of media.
It's a good thing.
We had a mandatory safety training today.
We have guys that had been here all night in the PDE and all night in the fire.
It's just more convenient.
It's better.
And we're still getting what we need, which is to make sure they have the info.
Okay.
Any other questions?
So you're just looking for the motion to approve the contract and authorize the manager.
So you're a signature?
Yes.
Motion to.
I'll make that motion.
Oh, second word.
You're a couple.
Lewis.
Johnson.
Weston.
Forester.
Shelton.
All right.
Christopher.
We have a list.
Looks like I got him 50.
The following commercial kitchen items are so close and authorized.
To be offered for sale through online auction.
That's different.
And that new for us?
It is now.
Okay.
Of course, it's obvious we're starting some remodeling already.
The efforts towards that.
We have some things going on simultaneously with the.
We have the large scale construction project plan.
We have some smaller in-house projects going on.
So we, that includes a remodel of the kitchen.
I say every model of it.
Basically on the scale at the end, it's going to be more of a catering type.
So we have these 15 items that we would like to surplus and make available.
To purchase through online auction.
And this is a cost savings for us.
A time saving effort.
We need to move that stuff out pretty quickly.
We really don't have a lot of space to store it.
If we were to wait for a traditional auction.
So we would like for you to continue to allow us to.
Consider it online auction.
And ask me to start plus these items.
Do we have any.
Leave a lot of vacation to the low-pile locally.
There's a new rush cost.
The statute actually.
When it comes to municipalities.
You have to surplus our items.
There's really no direction after that.
If we want to make items available for employees to be able to participate.
Then we have to do it through an auction of public auction process.
The public has to have the same opportunity to purchase.
And it's just a conservative public.
Yes.
What online auction service are you using?
We're looking at eBay right now.
Why are you just going to look at the OK?
And we, you know, one of the beautiful things is that we can make the requirements that they have to pick it up.
We will not be shipping out that monster size mixer that I can't even imagine how much that.
cost to ship anywhere. And the things that don't sell, we have the opportunity to use
for app for metal. But the revenue generated from the sale would go to these projects,
these additional in-house projects we have gone through.
Do we own the library building where the boys and girls club is?
Yes, what do you?
Would it be legal for us after these are determined to be surplus to install any of them in that facility
for the boys and girls club? I don't know either. I mean, I look like the grill maybe,
but I don't know how much of these stuff that they'd be interested in if any. But I don't
remember what kind of kitchen they have. I walked through it. I didn't really pay attention.
Maybe some shelving in the tables. One of the things that we're going to do is the
every all these, the smaller projects that we have going on, the stairs outside, the ADA concrete,
those are all budgeted. The kitchen remodel is not budgeted. So whatever we get off the sale of those,
we'll do that. But yeah, if you guys want a surplus and that's your choice to them.
I've been a lot of pancakes cooked on those and a lot of sausage in the past 10 years.
This is kind of a speak now referable to peace. So if you're okay with getting some of these three phase items,
you're not going to make sure does anyone know anything? There's a single phase of what?
What? Two twenty? One of them says is it two forty and two twenty two or four?
It's within ten percent. I don't know if it means anything to that question, but I think they're all from
the 50s. Second one. Second one. Second one. Yeah. Second one. The one else is a single phase or three phase.
I don't understand that. I don't know what it is here. I was just wondering if we'd be set up at the
Boys and Girls Club, but that convection oven and yeah, I mean we've already had interest in that.
That's nice. So the hood that you have to have for the fire, the fire exhaust hood, that has a penetration
So if you're wanting us to keep the grill and the oven, that has to have that hood.
It has to have a suppression system to be fried. And so if we get a little rid of those, we can get rid of
a penetration in the grill that we're getting ready to.
More likely if you get rid of one, you'll put them together. When you have a grill in the hood without
together, you'll just think of a way. If we've already had to sit or ring, if you're considering
putting them in the armory, then my question would be to bend. That is our property.
So we would not surplus those. I do, we would just move them. Transferring to.
Yeah. I don't know. I just want to help them with what can. If we're going somewhere to get 25.
It works hard and I would say if you're going to buy it, that's a great idea.
It needs a compressor.
It needs a work.
So I get, I know there's some more to see to this because you're trying to get this stuff out.
I don't know.
I mean, I can't, a larger convention, I don't know what that means.
If that's eight feet long or two feet tall or one.
Or packet, there were pictures, there were pictures, there were pictures.
Three feet by three feet.
I'm dealt with used restaurant equipment, not with 1950s models.
But there's a lot more current stuff on the market and I'd be really surprised if it's so quickly
and had a competitive price.
So am I allowed to bid on these, man?
Well, it is.
So if there was something that I just wanted to bid on and donate to the Boise Girls Club,
I could.
Okay.
Or anyone else.
But in the council member.
I believe I'm trying to keep the process moving along, but if there is something that they could really use,
then it was a bit odd to you.
Well, in one of the options we have on eBay is to set a minimum.
Yeah.
Do you list those at a minimum price?
We can.
Yes.
Yeah, because you come in here and just, you know, get it for nothing and then scrap it.
And then it's stainless pretty high.
And then how do you price it at home?
He has.
Well, my thought was, I would try to get an idea of maybe what it would draw, what it would bring as a scrap.
And consider my minimums of that.
I don't know.
I don't know how you lift that mixer.
I mean, I don't know.
I'll take my bet that that mixer brings the most money.
Probably will.
And it is not right here.
It is.
It is a restaurant coming in and starting up right here.
It should be.
And of course we're going to see them.
I don't know.
So if we take this step of declaring them so close to night.
And somebody from the Boys and Girls Club came over tomorrow and said, oh, wait, we could build
you as that and that.
We've got somebody that could fix that.
Do we still have the discretion?
You can always remove items from your surplus.
Okay.
I'll be.
Good.
I mean.
So what do we do there?
Yeah.
Is that okay?
Yes.
At least give them a chance to look at it.
And if there's something that they, they're on expense, want to get and fix that.
Well, I'm just even thinking.
the shelving and the tables your tables will probably be your next. I mean we built
two but that's what it gets. I don't know about 20 kids.
Sedexos doing the catering form and I mean they have been real busy according to my wife.
So I guess I take nothing ballroom near Grant saying anything ballroom near the kitchen.
The real lot of sports in the middle of the occasion now are anyone.
And we've got a church express interest that has a camp. They're setting up a new camp and they're
interested in a few things. So we're going to, if you choose to serve class, we'll put the
information about the auction and the window for the auction. On our website, we will put it in the
news record as well. Of course anyone watching has the opportunity to understand that we'll be
putting together the opportunity. When to get the word out as far as we can.
What's your eBay user name? I do not have to pay a lot of that. I think the one I'm going to go with
that. That's the easiest one. Okay. So there's perhaps interest by the boys and those
clubs that are Riverbomb's Brooklyn Grove, a church group. I hate to see something get split
within part of it's wasted. We need to make sure we package them however we're talking about with the
girlhood or whatever suppose. Beyond that, any questions? We have a motion to approve,
so I'm focusing the other question. You guys are really needing to give me the message to start working there.
What do we re-locating staff into the banquet range? Have what point is that going to take place?
Well, we're moving this day this week into the diner. I'm going to have me put, I mean you really don't want
to move this twice, so you're trying to look at it. Okay. All the questions. Okay. We have a motion to
surplus at the items listed under a gender item. Good thing. Make a motion? Well, and our
horizon would be offered for sale with doing the online auction, knowing that we have the discretion
that unsurpassed something if we want to put it in our building. Okay. Okay. Okay. We have a second.
Four-pop list. Four-pop list. Western list, Johnson. All right.
Item 16. Resolution CC2017-13 transferring up to 2.4 million from the rainy day following the
capital improvement fund is needed in posing the requirement that all annual budgets are prepared
by the city manager provide for an investment of no less than 3.72 to 3.32 to the rainy day fund.
transforming man has been restored to the rainy day finally and what sort of amortization is that
G.L. like through 72232 times what equals 2.4 million.
It's a six years.
We've already put in an additional 15616 which is what we put in this fiscal year.
It's zero interest.
So by the six year payback.
Yeah.
And this number is different than the number we discussed before and that's because what?
Well, we opened the bids for the Civic Center renovation and the bid total that we received
as in the neighborhood of 1.7 million.
However, it did not include all of the items that we were asking for bids for.
Okay.
And so plus and we're going to get to this underneath business.
We're going to ask to rebuild the roofing project and we'll explain that when we get to that point.
So that 700 square does that include the roof and then the other components that we still need to get beds on.
And what we are not sure we're going to find when you're going to open the building.
Well, the 1.7 does include the bids on the roof.
Okay.
But as I said, we're going to ask to redo that.
So you're just looking for the 2.4 number now and you think that's a pretty safe number.
It is everybody's best guess that that will cover everything that has been discussed on the renovations of the building.
And leave us a fairly good cushion for all the unknowns that we're going to give you.
Not too.
You never watched fix your effort.
We're going to do the whole thing at this age.
Yes.
And that's why it's it's turned as up to the 10th or 14th.
When displacements are may Jill will those come back before the council or just as claims how will the council be able to kind of monitor what's happening.
We're going to be doing well.
We're going to start in project accounting because we've actually already paid architects and money.
And yes, you guys, you will see this claims.
So there'll be claims and in similar to like the stadium project we'll have.
Exactly.
Reporting.
The tier will.
Here's where we are.
The next.
Think to occur is for a cross look construction.
Who is our construction manager at risk.
They will come and present you with a plan which will include a guaranteed maximum price.
the council has to approve that price to move forward and or we have to issue notice to proceed.
But that will be, I think we'll do that till we get the big fine lines.
We can issue notice to proceed.
The plan still is for them to come on the fifth of July.
Although if we rebuild the roofs, those beds will come in on the sixth of July.
So we're still talking about that.
Any questions on item 16?
I know there's a, we're going to have,
bring some clarity to the roof issue a little bit later in the meeting.
Any questions or concerns on item 16?
That's not going to change that three so until you run the right.
But I think that is reflected in that three 72.
I'm sorry, what's the question?
I've got a lot of that.
The 372 payback, that's going to change according to you.
What will you end up spending now for the final?
This, this year we have three 72, 232 in the budget.
And if we get two and four, we're going to, we're going to pay it over here.
If we hit two two, then that last year we'll pay one 72.
We might adjust it next budget soon.
Okay.
May read it really.
I'll try it at that point.
Okay.
And the, with what we're talking about between this and the next resolution,
that it still leaves us with 4.375 376 in the rainy day fund.
Okay.
At this time, June 30th and 18.
Because we've made that 372 and then 11,695 payment by that time now.
Okay.
So, do we have a motion to approve resolution CC2017-133?
Motion approved.
May.
In a second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Two.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Okay.
So, I'll, excuse me, I was 17 as resolution in 16.
So, one second.
Which will be transferring 96,400 from the rainy day fund.
M2DMDRA fund.
And imposing requirement that our budgets from poor by the city manager provide for an
investment of no less than 11695.
Two to the rainy day fund from MDRA into the transfer of demand has been restored to the rainy day fund.
And if, if you recall, if you've given us a serve on the NRA and we have a loan and approximately that amount,
with first national bank, that NDRA is currently paying and also paying 4.5% interest.
Since we have a large amount of money in the rainy day fund that we're not really earning anything close to that.
on, I had asked for the Council to consider advancing those funds on behalf of the MDRA to pay
off the no-to-first national bank thereby saving, I think, 2700 a year in interest, at least
in the first couple of years, and I'm not less than that.
About 28,000 total over the life of the note, and so this resolution, I guess, is a here kind
of, at mine, the old request, we didn't make sense for the city to do that.
So I would ask, if there's any discussion or questions, if not, do we have a motion to approve
a resolution CC2-017-14?
Also, I can only bring a motion per, let's let you and I go ahead.
Go ahead.
For a step?
All right.
No, this is Johnson.
Question?
All right.
In short.
Back.
Thank you.
I just want to have a look.
Yeah, yeah.
I do.
All right.
Out of 18, fiscal year 2017-28, municipal budget, budget, budget.
Basit?
What if that says?
That's kind of wrong.
We're bringing a city of Miami over home, a budget, for the fiscal year,
2017-28, and establishing budget amendment authority.
And that's the end of that agenda.
I am jail on Wednesday.
So a couple of the changes since the last time we have discussed the budget numbers.
We have added in the expenditure of the donation that $5,000 donation from the Intertribal Council
for the fence.
We have recalculated carryover.
It also includes the change in the rainy day fund,
the two that you just approved.
That's the change in the $5,000.
Did you say that?
Yeah.
That's the first thing I said.
She said fence and that's in reverse.
Yes.
Okay.
Any questions?
We've had our public hearing.
Right?
Yes.
And so statutory now we need to approve the budget.
Recognizing that there's amendments of the order in there we need to make changes later.
Yes.
And it also, the budget message also includes a certification page on the very last page for the rainy day fund balance.
And it just reiterates the amounts that we're taking out and what the amounts will be in that fund at the end of the year.
And that amount was to repeat that amount, please.
June 30th of 18, we're projecting it'll be 4,376, 177.
And you're saying 18 because it's the end of the next fiscal year that we're projecting that for.
Yes.
Any questions?
Do we have a motion to?
resolution number related to it. So we're just approving the budget and the resolution and the
certification and the certification and the certification that are part of the budget.
Yes. We have a motion. I'll make the motion.
And a second. I'm second.
We'll call please.
Question.
because when we did the bid openings for the Civic Center renovation, through an error
on our part, one of the bids for the roof was not opened at the public hearing for the
bid open. And so it was discovered after the fact that we had failed to include that and
then we did open it at the request of cross-line construction and of course it ended up being
lower than any of the other bids that we had received.
Which is a good thing. It's a good thing. But that presents the problem of if we were to accept
the lowest bid that was presented at the open meeting, then I think we would be open to some
potential liability to the individual but had done everything properly with the actual lowest
bid, but which was not open to at the meeting. Or conversely, if we accepted that bid, we would
be open to liability from the person that had the lowest bid that was properly open because
the other bid was not legally dealt with at the meeting. So consequently, it's my opinion and we've
also run this by being and Georgian because that's really her area of what she deals with.
We all feel that it would be best at this point to reject all of the roofing bids and reopen
that one item.
and open them properly at that point.
It can be done as quickly as July 6,
but with the advertising requirements and the timeframes that the law requires,
that's the earliest that we could do it.
But the reason we wanted to do this tonight,
first of all, cross-link construction as the CMA
are kind of is regulating the whole transaction.
But they let us know today that it was their opinion
that we have to reject the bid,
and I would tend to agree with that after reviewing the contract.
That's why we think it can be done today,
and we wanted to do it today,
so as to get the process moving as quickly as we can to keep on this.
As close as we can to the schedule that was contemplated
in this entire transaction.
Then there's a public body like this,
always have the discretion to reject all of it.
So we have no requirement to ever, you can always do that.
You do it ten times in a row. You want to do it directly.
Correct.
So there's no liability in that respect to us that we're going out for bids in here.
The liability is that you have to pay their costs.
Every time you advertise and all that,
but no liability in the form of exposure to lawsuits.
Just to be clear, this bid was here on time.
It was no fault if it was properly submitted.
And it was our fault, the city's fault.
Air on the staff members.
So here is rejecting our requesting that we reject all roof bids
as part of the project.
And rebuild them as quickly as possible.
And so would it be appropriate to do that in the form of emotion
or just indicate that that's our desire?
Or I would recommend the emotion.
So under the new business item,
because we have something that just come up and was not able to be anticipated.
Staff is requesting the motion to reject all roof bids
related to the remodel project.
And in addition to that, instructions are re-bid as quickly as is reasonably possible.
Do we have a motion?
Do we have a second?
Second.
We'll call please.
Johnson, Lewis, I've left him.
I've left him.
in the house, and the announcements?
Here you can mention.
Well, I've missed the staff reports.
I don't know anybody here.
I can mention it.
I have a splash bag on.
We're on time with it or I'm heading out dates for.
You know?
Maybe my ear can actually help.
I'm pulling that.
That's what I'm talking about.
I like it too.
Everything that I'm looking for,
I'm looking for a craft of a way
that nobody's going on.
And that over there to give us all.
They're, they found more chap than they expected to.
And they're having to deal with that.
The state is.
I thought I kind of had a cushion anyway.
They didn't have any time.
I'm not sure on that one.
Because originally we're hoping to do a case sheet.
Yeah.
But the offer lights really should have been like 10 and a day.
It's all about this one.
Any other questions, comments, announcements?
I have.
There's one other item.
Jill on.
Do you mind you?
Let this will be the last meeting.
That we'll be televised.
I on cable one.
Unless we.
We do our agreement with them at a later date.
It's also going to be the last meeting in this room.
Until the renovation.
Well, it's the last meeting in this room.
Yeah.
But the next meeting will be in what is now the ballroom of the dining room.
So I don't get the cable one part.
Well, cable one.
We do not have a hook up to get to cable one.
So we will not be televising this meeting on cable one through the rehab.
Which will be six to eight months.
And then we'll need to get a decision on whether to have cable one.
I don't have that on the gym.
All right.
But we have the right to broadcast.
You're saying it's just not feasible.
That during this transition and then we'll look at making sure.
We're still doing a live stream.
Okay.
But just not cable one.
If they're on it.